Xavier University Division of University Relations records
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
Xavier University Division of University Relations records
1928-2015
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Division of University Relations
4.5 linear feet (9 boxes)
This collection of University Relations materials includes publications, correspondence and other items relating to annual fund raising efforts and other related issues. Some activities originally located in the Division of University Relations, with documents found in this collection, have been recently transferred to the Office of the Administrative Vice President. Such is the case with the Xavier Speakers program.
XUA-89
History of the Division of University Relations
Publicity and Public Relations was at one time included in the Division of University Relations. Subsequently this function has been transferred to the Office of the Administrative Vice President of Xavier University.
Scope and Content
This collection of records reflects activity by the Xavier University Division of University Relations. Items chiefly concern various annual fund raising efforts done by the university and the administrative records of Vice President Edward P. VonderHaar.
Statement of Arrangement
This collection is arranged into five series, as follows: Series I. Organizational Charts and Related Materials, 1966-2015 Series II. Annual Fund Raising Programs, 1934-2015 Series III. Vice Presidents Records, 1928-2001 Series IV. Publications and Brochures, 1933-2015 Series V. Miscellaneous, 1934-2011
Restrictions on Access
Some materials may have restricted access. Please contact the archives staff.
Acquisition Information
These materials have been collected from various sources.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Educational Fund Raising--Ohio
Organizations/Corporations:
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)-- Public relations; Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)-- Finance; Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Vice President for University Relations
Detailed Description of The Collection
- Series I. Organizational Charts and Related Materials, 1966-1973; 2015; undated
  - Division Historical Dates, Organizational Charts and Job Descriptions, 1966-1973; 2015; undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II. Annual Fund Raising Programs, 1934-2015
  - Annual Fund Raising: Booster Club: 1934; Xavier Associates Program: 1955-1956, 1933-1955; undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Annual Fund Raising: Blue and White Derby Fund Drive, 1954; undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Annual Fund Raising: Gonser and Gerber Visits, 1954-1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Annual Fund Drives: Dads United For Xavier, 1942-1963 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Annual Fund Drives: Dads United for Xavier, 1964-1974; undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Annual Fund Raising: Businessmen Mobilized For Xavier Annual Brochures, 1953-1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Annual Fund Raising: Businessmen Mobilized For Xavier Annual Brochures, 1967-1992 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Annual Fund Raising: Business Mobilized For Xavier Correspondence, 1959-1966; undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Annual Fund Raising: Businessmen Mobilized For Xavier Correspondence, 1967-1981; undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Annual Fund Drives: Living Endowment Fund, 1955-1963 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Annual Fund Raising: Living Endowment Fund, 1963-1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Annual Fund Raising: Living Endowment Fund:1970 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Annual Fund Raising: Senior Class Remembrance Fund, 1960; 1966; undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Annual Fund Drive: Gift and Estate Planning (Planned Giving), 1944; 1961-2015 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Annual Fund Raising: Annual Fund, 1985-2002; undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Annual Fund Raising: Annual Fund, 2005-2012 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Annual Fund Raising: The 1831 Society, 2003-2013 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Annual Fund Raising: Williams College of Business Corporate Partners, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Honor Roll of Giving, 1974-1982; undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Honor Roll of Giving, 1983-1993 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Series III. Vice Presidents Records, 1928-2001
  - Gioielli_William_R, Vice President for University Relations, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Lindsay_Paul_L_Director of Alumni Affairs, Associate Vice President for Special Events, 1970; 1974 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Massa_Gary_R_Vice President for University Relations, 2001 Jamuary 18 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Sandman_Joseph_G_Director of Government and Foundation Relations, Vice President for University Relations and Advancement, 1976-1979; 1992 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Sassen_James_W_Vice President for Public Relations and Development, 1974; undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - VonderHaar_Edward_P_Vice President for Public Relations and Development Correspondence, 1941-1959 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - VonderHaar_Edward_P_Vice President for Public Relations and Development Correspondence, 1960-1964 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - VonderHaar_Edward_P_Vice President for Public Relations and Development Correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - VonderHaar_Edward_P_Vice President for Public Relations and Development Correspondence, 1968; undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - VonderHaar_Edward_P_Vice President for Public Relations and Development Correspondence, 1969 January-June (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - VonderHaar_Edward_P_Vice President for Public Relations and Development Correspondence, 1969 July-December (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - VonderHaar_Edward_P_Vice President for Public Relations and Development Correspondence, 1970 January-June (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - VonderHaar_Edward_P_Vice President for Public Relations and Development Correspondence, 1970 July-December (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - VonderHaar_Edward_P_Vice President for Public Relations and Development Correspondence, 1971 January-June (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - VonderHaar_Edward_P_Vice President for Public Relations and Development Correspondence, 1971 July-December (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - VonderHaar_Edward_P_Vice President for Public Relations and Development Personal Correspondence, 1949-1966 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - VonderHaar_Edward_P_Vice President for Public Relations and Development Personal Correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - VonderHaar_Edward_P_Vice President Speeches, Poems, Writings, 1941-1967 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - VonderHaar_Edward_P_Vice President Notes on Xavier History, 1950-1970, 1936-1969 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - VonderHaar_Edward_P_Vice President Life, Career, and Death, 1926-1983 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Weber_Charles_T_Assistant Director of Development, Director of Foundation Relations, 1960-1968 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Series IV. Publications ad Brochures, 1933-2015
  - Publication: XU News Service, Weekly Release, 1933-1936 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Publication: The Dorm Form: Elet Hall, 1945 March-October (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Publication: Xavier....As I See It, 1950-1955 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    This folder contains only sporadic issues of this publication. Although officially issued from the President's Office, this publication is considered to be done principally through the auspices of the the development office at Xavier University.
  - Publication: X-cerpts, Newsletter for High School Students, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Brochure: Xavier University-- An Introduction, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Brochure: America's Need: Great Teaching, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    This brochure was used to solicit funding for the university. It served also as a view book to the campus. A section on proposed buildings for the campus gives artist's renderings of proposed campus buildings.
  - Founders' Day Celebrations, 1998-2009 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    This folder includes DVD of the 2009 Founders' Day celebration.
  - Founders' "Day Celebrations, 2010-2015 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Includes DVDs for the 2010 Founders' Day Smith Hall and Quad Opening and also "The Legacy of Fr. James Hoff, S.J." presentation shown at the Founders' Day Dinner, September 23, 2010.
    DVD contents have been copied and placed in the archives permanent drive.
  - Media Guide and Faculty Speakers, 1960-2002 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Media Guide and Faculty Speakers, 2002-2005 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Media Guide and Faculty Speakers, 2006-2012 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Series V. Miscellaneous, 1934-2011
  - Marketing Xavier in the Commercial Press, 1961-1970; undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Coordinating Committee of Xavier University and St. Xavier High School, 1940-1948 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Visitors to Xavier from Japan, 1934; 1956 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - United Nations Drama: Cincinnati Plan for United Nations, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Jesuit Province Development Conference, 1957 December (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Mrs. A.B. Cohen Essay Contest; Cohen Award for Excellence in Teaching, 1962-1963; 1965 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Xavier Relations With Neighboring Communities, 1979-2004 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    This folder contains only a few scattered items relating to Xavier relations in the community.
  - Brochures About Xavier, 1948-1995 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Division Policies and Procedures Manuals, 1970-2011 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Financial Reports on Giving, 1967; 1987; undated (Box 9, Folder 9)